freepixels.com 2018-09-23

# Privacy Policy • www.freepixels.com

This website collects personal data for the following purposes using the following services:

  * Contacting the User
    * Contact form
      * Type of personal data: email address, first name and last name
  * Advertising
    * Google AdSense
      * Type of  personal data: Cookies and Usage Data
  * Analytics
    * Google Analytics with anonymized IP, WordPress Stats and Google Analytics
      * Type of personal data: Cookies and Usage Data
  * Displaying content from external social media platforms
    * Instagram widget
      * Type of personal data: Cookies and Usage Data
    * Google Fonts
      * Type of personal data: Usage Data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
  * Tag Management
    * Google Tag Manager
      * Type of personal data: Cookies and Usage Data
  * Interaction with external social networks and platforms
    * Pinterest “Pin it” button, Twitter Tweet button, Facebook Like button, Google+ +1 button and social widgets
      * Type of personal data: Cookies and Usage Data

Owner and Data Controller

Adrian Claudiu Pana

124 Ion Minulescu

031216 Bucharest

Romania

Owner contact email: [adrian@freepixels.com](mailto:adrian@freepixels.com)

## Definitions

#### Personal data

Personal data is any information that relates to an identified or identifiable living individual. Different pieces of information, which collected together can lead to the identification of a particular person, also constitute personal data.

#### Usage data

All information collected automatically through this website including  third-party services employed in this website which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the users who access this website, the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server’s answer, the country of origin, the user’s browser and operating system, the various time details per visit (ex: the time spent on each page within the website) and the details about the path followed within the website especially referring to the sequence of pages visited.

#### User

The individual who uses this website and who coincides with the data subject.

#### Data subject

Data subject refers to any individual person who can be identified, directly or indirectly, via an identifier such as a name, an ID number, location data, or via factors specific to the person’s physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity. In other words, a data subject is an end user whose personal data can be collected.

#### Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes personal data on behalf of the controller.

#### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of personal data.In our case the data controller is the owner of this website.

#### Security

the owner of this website adopted security measures concerning the operation and use of this Website. 

#### Cookies

Cookies are small piece of data sent from a website and stored on the user’s computer by the user’s web browser while the user is browsing. Cookies are sent to your browser from a web site and stored on user’s computer hard drive.  
  
We use “cookies” to collect information. You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. 

### Types of Data collected

These are the types of personal data that this website collects, by itself or through third parties: first name, last name, email address, cookies and usage data.

Personal data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using this website ( in case of usage data) .

The use of cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this website or by the owners of third-party services used by this website serves the purpose of providing the service required by the user, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document.

Data requested by this website is mandatory and failure to provide this data may

make it impossible for this website to provide its services such as support.

### Methods of processing the data:

Processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the owner or by a third party.

The data is processed at the owner’s operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.Depending on the user’s location, data transfers may involve transferring the user’s data to a foreign country.

Personal data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for meaning that personal data collected for the purposes of the owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by the owner within this document or by contacting the owner.

As long as user consent is not withdrawn the owner may be allowed to retain personal data for a longer period whenever the user has given consent to such processing.

Once the retention period expires, personal data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right to access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification or the right to data portability cannot be implemented after expiration of the retention period.

### The purposes of processing

The data in connection to the user is harvested to allow the owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: contacting the user, analytics, advertising, displaying content from external platforms, interaction with external social networks and platforms, SPAM protection and Tag Management.

Personal data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

  * #### Advertising

This type of service allows user data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on this website, possibly based on user interests.

This does not mean that all personal data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.

Some of the services listed below may use cookies to identify users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the user’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside this Website. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.

In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the user may opt out of a third-party service’s use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

##### Google AdSense (Google Inc.)

Google AdSense is an advertising service provided by Google Inc. Users may decide to disable all the Doubleclick Cookies(used by Google Inc. to track use of this website and user behaviour) by clicking on: [google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout](http://google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout).

Personal data collected: Cookies and usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout). Privacy Shield participant.

  * #### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the owner to analyze how users use the site.

##### Google Analytics with IP anonymization (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer to track and examine the use of this website, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.

This integration of Google Analytics anonymize your IP address. It works by shortening users’ IP addresses within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the complete IP address be sent to a Google server and shortened within the US. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser.

Personal data collected: Cookies and usage data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). Google Inc. is a Privacy Shield participant.

##### WordPress Stats (Automattic Inc.)

WordPress Stats is an analytics service provided by Automattic Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookies and usage data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/). Automattic Inc. is an Active Participant în the Privacy Shield Framework.

##### Google Analytics (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Website, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.

Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal data collected: Cookies and usage data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). Google Inc. is a Privacy Shield participant.

  * #### Contacting the User

##### Contact form (this Website)

By filling in the contact form with their data, the user authorizes this website to use these details to reply to requests for information indicated in the form.

Personal data collected: email address, first name and last name.

  * #### Displaying content from external platforms

This type of service allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this website and interact with them.

This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when users do not use it.

##### Instagram widget (Instagram, Inc.)

Instagram is an image visualization service provided by Instagram, Inc. that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal data collected: Cookies and usage data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/). Facebook, Inc. is an Active Participant în the Privacy Shield Framework.

##### Google Fonts (Google Inc.)

Google Fonts is a typeface visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal data collected: usage data and various types of data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.it/intl/policies/privacy/). Google Inc. is a Privacy Shield participant.

  * #### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

This service allows interaction with social networks directly from the pages of this website.

The interaction and information obtained through this website are always subject to the user’s privacy settings for each social network.

##### Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets (Pinterest)

The Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Pinterest platform provided by Pinterest Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookies and usage data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy).

##### Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (Twitter, Inc.)

The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter, Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookies and usage data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy). Privacy Shield participant.

##### Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook, Inc.)

The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook, Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookies and usage data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation). Facebook, Inc. is an Active Participant în the Privacy Shield Framework.

##### Google+ +1 button and social widgets (Google Inc.)

The Google+ +1 button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Google+ social network provided by Google Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookies and usage data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/policies/privacy/). Google Inc. is a Privacy Shield participant.

  * #### Tag Management

This type of service helps the Owner to manage the tags or scripts needed on this Website in a centralized fashion.

This results in the Users’ Data flowing through these services, potentially resulting in the retention of this Data.

##### Google Tag Manager (Google LLC)

Google Tag Manager is a tag management service provided by Google LLC.

Personal data collected: Cookies and usage data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/). Google Inc. is a Privacy Shield participant.

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their data processed by the owner. Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in this document. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by the Owner as early as possible and always within one month.

Users have the right to do the following:

  * Withdraw their consent given to us at any time. Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their personal data.
  * Object to processing of their data. Users have the right to object to the processing of their data if grounds for this relating to their particular situation exist or the objection is to direct marketing.
  * to obtain information about the personal data processed by us.
  * Verify and seek rectification. Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.
  * Restrict the processing of their data. Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their data. 
  * Have their personal data erased or otherwise removed. Users have the right, unless the processing is necessary for exercising the right of freedom of expression or information, for compliance with a legal obligation, for reasons of public interest or for the establishment exercise or defense of legal claims, to obtain the erasure of their data from the owner.
  * Receive their data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and have it transferred to another controller.

#### Changes to this privacy policy

The owner reserves the right to amend this privacy policy at any time. It is strongly recommended to check this policy, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom.

### Legal information

This privacy policy has been prepared based on provisions of multiple legislations, including Art. 13/14 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (General Data Protection Regulation).
